#### M +86 15997431443

#### 15997431443@163.com

## https://home.cnblogs.com/u/Jadie

#### 概况

我有3年工作经验,其中2年性能测试经验,2年功能自动化测试经验,1年系统测试经验。 经历不同类型的测试工作并且在多个项目中独立负责测试工作后,我对各种类型的测试方法 和流程十分熟悉,善于针对不同项目的特点制定不同的测试策略,并且热衷于在项目中使用 敏捷测试。在跟国外客户沟通和汇报,跟异地同事合作项目的过程中锻炼出了良好的沟通能 力、英语能力和跨地区协作能力。另外我乐于学习新技术,抗压能力强,喜欢接受挑战。

#### 技能

UFT	18个月
Selenium	6个月
LoadRunner	24个月
JMeter	12个月
JavaScript	6个月

# 经历

普华信联(武汉)科技有限公司	中高级测试工程师	医疗	2018/5-至今
武汉玖信普惠金融信息服务有限公司	自动化测试工程师	金融	2017/9-2018/4
武汉斗鱼网络科技有限公司	性能测试工程师	互联网	2017/5-2017/8
惠普企业服务(武汉)有限公司	性能测试工程师	制造业	2015/4-2017/5

#### 项目

医商云 2018/5-至今

**项目类型**:功能自动化测试 **项目角色**:自动化测试负责人

**工作内容:** 1. GUI自动化测试工具选型及推广。选定Robot Framework+Selenium作为GUI自动化测试工具,并在一个月内写好基础控件,搭建完成针对本项目的自动化框架,并推广到整个测试组内使用。

- 2. 接口自动化测试平台选型、环境搭建及推广。选取eoLinker平台作为接口管理平台,使得接口集中管理,重复使用,开发编写接口文档时间节约50%,接口自测时间节省90%,测试进行接口测试的接口录入时间节省100%,前端进行mock开发的接口录入时间节省100%。
- 3. 对TAPD中的bug报表进行分析,找到bug产生的人为原因,并通过相关负责人对其团队成员进行针对性能力提升。方案实施后实施人员bug误报率每月环比减少20%,测试漏测率环比减少10%,测试中bug率环比减少15%。
- 4. 系统测试。根据项目特点编写测试用例并测试。

使用技术: Robot Framework, Selenium, EoLinker, TAPD

#### 项目(接上页)

玖融网 2017/9-2018/4

项目类型: GUI自动化测试

项目角色: GUI自动化测试负责人

**工作内容:** 1. 自动化工具选型。从易用性、快速开发脚本和ERP产品的独特属性三方面选取了UFT作为GUI自动化测试工具。

- 2. 用UFT编写玖融网erp端风控审批流程的自动化测试脚本。
- 3. 通过GUI自动化测试脚本为ERP做回归测试。
- 4. 系统测试。根据项目特点编写测试用例并测试。

使用技术: UFT, 禅道

#### 斗鱼Web端性能巡检

2017/5-2017/8

项目类型: 性能测试

项目角色: 性能巡检负责人

**工作内容:** 1. 从功能测试小组收集所有业务模块,组织开发、功能测试、性能测试人员评审,确定巡检范围。

- 2. 跟大数据小组合作,导出最近一周用户访问量前500的接口数据,分析出用户使用场景,确定巡检结果指标,制定了30多个测试场景。
- 3. 开发JMeter脚本,执行测试,监控服务器资源使用情况。

使用技术: JMeter

**P&G MES** 2015/4-2017/5

项目类型: 性能测试

项目角色: 性能测试负责人

工作内容: 1. 性能测试需求收集。由于新系统没有历史性能数据参考,所以参考了行业通用准则,MES系统用户使用特征,及客户需求,整理出了性能测试范围、场景及指标。

- 2. 设定测试计划和方案。
- 3. 执行测试方案。编写和调试LoadRunner测试脚本,设定符合实际生产环境的测试场景,执行测试,监控性能指标。
- 4. 协助开发进行系统调优后,再次测试发现性能提升80%。

使用技术: LoadRunner, UFT

教育

湖北,武汉,武汉轻工大学 – 本科,网络工程,2015级湖北,武汉,武汉轻工大学 – 双学位,英语,2015级

# Yao Xiaoyu

M +86 15997431443 15997431443@163.com

https://home.cnblogs.com/u/Jadie/

#### **Summary**

I have 3 years working experience, including 2 years of performance testing experience, 2 years of automation testing experience, 1 year of system testing experience. After experiencing different types of testing work and being independently responsible for testing work in multiple projects, I am very familiar with various types of testing methods and processes, good at formulating different testing strategies according to the characteristics of different projects, and keen to use agile testing in projects.

In the process of communicating and reporting with foreign customers and cooperating with colleagues from other countries or cities, I have developed good communication skills, English skills and cross-regional collaboration skills. In addition, I am willing to learn new technology, strong pressure resistance, enjoy challenges.

#### **Expertise**

UFT	18 Months
Selenium	6 Months
LoadRunner	24 Months
JMeter	12 Months
JavaScript	6 Months

## Experience

# PHXL (Wuhan) Technology Co.,Ltd.

2018/5-Now

Industry: Medical Care

Position: Senior Software Testing Engineer

Wuhan Jiuxin Inclusive Financial Information Service Co., Ltd. 2017/9-2018/4

Industry: Finance

Position: Automation Tester

Wuhan Douyu Network Technology Co., Ltd. 2017/5-2017/8

Industry: Internet

Position: Performance Tester

Hewlett Packard Enterprise Service (Wuhan) Co., Ltd. 2015/4-2017/5

Industry: Manufacturing Position: Performance Tester

#### **Project**

#### **Medical and Business Cloud**

2018/5-Now

Type: Automation Testing

Role: Automation Testing Leader

Activity: 1. GUI automation test tool selection and promotion. I built the automation

framework for this project and extended to the testing team in a month.

2. Interface automation management platform selection, environment building and platform promotion. The eoLinker platform is selected to make the interface management centralized and reusable, saving 50% of the time for developer to write interface documents, 90% of the time for developer to do self-testing, 100% of the time for front-end developer to format interface to do mock test, 100% of the time for tester to formatting interface for testing.

#### Project(Continued)

- 3. Analysed the bug report in TAPD, find out the human reasons for the bug, and improve the performance of the team members through their leaders. After the implementation of the scheme, the false alarm rate from the Implementation Engineer is reduced by 20% compared a month earlier, the missed test rate by 10% compared a month earlier and the bug rate by 15% compared a month earlier.
- 4. System testing. Developing test cases and test them according to project characteristics.

**Tools:** Robot Framework, Selenium, EoLinker, TAPD

Jiurong Website 2017/9-2018/4

Type: GUI Automation Testing

Role: GUI Automation Testing Leader

**Activity:** 1. Automation tool selection. UFT was selected as the GUI automated testing tool from three aspects: easy for use, rapid for development and suitable for ERP products.

- 2. Used UFT to develop automation test scripts for ERP terminal.
- 3. Did regression testing for ERP through GUI automation test script.
- 4. System testing. Developing test cases and test them according to project characteristics.

Tools: UFT, ZenTao

# **Douyu Performance Test for Inspecting**

2017/5-2017/8

**Type:** Performance Testing **Role:** Project Leader

**Activity:** 1. Collected all business modules from the functional testing team; organized developer, functional tester, performance tester review and determine the scope of the inspecting test.

- 2. Cooperated with big data group to export the top 500 interfaces data of the user visits in the last week, analyzed user scenarios, determined inspecting test goal, and developed more than 30 test scenarios.
- 3. Developed JMeter scripts, executed tests, monitored server resources usage.

**Tools:** JMeter

P&G MES 2015/4-2017/5

Type: Performance Testing

Role: Performance Testing Leader

**Activity:** 1. Performance test requirement collection. Since the new system had no historical performance data reference, the scope, scenarios and indicators of performance testing was sorted out by referring to industry general guidelines, user characteristics of MES system and customer needs.

- 2. Set test plans and plans.
- 3. Executed the test plan. Wrote and debug LoadRunner test scripts, set test scenarios with the actual production environment, executed tests, and monitored performance indicators.
- 4. Assisted with the developer of system tuning, tested again found that the performance improved by 80%.

Tools: LoadRunner. UFT

# Education

Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan, Hubei – Bachelor, Network Engineering, 2015 Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan, Hubei – Bachelor, English, 2015